我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother
被令人难以置信的东西杀害
by something impossible.
巴里  快跑
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度打击犯罪
but secretly I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me,
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day I'll find who killed my mother...
-妈妈  -让我父亲沉冤得雪
- Mom. - And get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously, on the Flash and Arrow...
我就是不能确定自己是否和你一样  奥利弗
I'm just not sure I'm like you, Oliver.
我不知道自己是否能做好一个治安维持者
I don't know if I can be some vigilante.
你能做得更好
You can be better,
因为你能以一种我无法做到的方式
because you can inspire people
激励大家  鼓舞大家
in a way that I never could.
你说你写我的故事是想
You said you were writing about me to bring hope
被一道闪光拯救
给你在乎的人带去希望
to someone you care about.
但若你这样让自己身处险境  他会作何感想
How would he feel if doing that put you in harm's way?
你给了很多人希望
You're giving hope to a lot of people.
所以我这么做是为了他们
So I'm doing this for them.
巴里  你刚见到我 奥利弗和狄格时
Barry, when you met me, Oliver, and Dig,
我们就像上好油的射箭机器般紧密无间
we were this well-oiled archery machine,
但是一开始并不是这样的
but it didn't start out that way.
对不起  今晚没能及时救你
I'm sorry I wasn't there for you tonight.
你值得我准时出现
You're worth being on time for.
地球上的每个人在生命中的某些特定时刻
Everyone on this planet, at some point in their lives,
都会有一种特殊的感觉...
has had a major case of the feels--
也就是你的心太小
Those days when your heart is just too small
难以装下你感觉到的大事
to hold the big things you're feeling.
今天就是如此
Today's one of those days.
我们觉得我们的感觉是独一无二的
We think of our emotions like they're these unique,
个人现象
personal phenomena,
觉得没有其他人感受过我们的感受
that no one has ever felt what we have felt.
其实我们的情感都是有科学依据的
There is a basis in science for every emotion we feel--
比如愤怒和爱
anger, love.
作为一个科学家  我知道
As a scientist, I know there's nothing magical
一个人对另一个人的感觉没什么神奇之处
about what makes us feel something for someone else...
但是我看到了她的笑容
but then I see her smile.
老天  那简直太不科学了
Man, that cannot be science.
黄金城市银行  中城人民的保险箱
对了  冰箱里还有一瓶没开装的
Oh, and there's a fresh bottle in the fridge
等她睡起来喝就行
when she wakes up from her nap.
谢谢
Thank you.
先生  请问有什么可以帮你的吗
Sir? Help you with something?
谢谢
Thanks.
我自己一个人就行
I'll be just fine on my own.
先生  您不能来这里
Sir, you're not allowed to be back here.
没事  不用担心
Nothing to get upset about.
巴里
Barry,
坎宁安和萨佩尔街处发生银行抢劫案
bank robbery in progress at Cunningham and Sampere.
收到
I got it.
什么  我的钱都存在那里
Wait, that's where I bank.
一旦超能力窃贼出现
Once super thieves showed up,
我就马上投入战斗状态
I went mattress.
我都已经错过健身时间了
I've already missed the gym.
不要嘛  再待五分钟
Ugh, no. Five more minutes.
好嘛  我们从没睡过懒觉
Come on, we never get to sleep in.
我知道  但是你爸可不喜欢别人迟到
I know. But your dad hates tardiness.
是不是很扫兴
Buzzkill.
扫兴到爆
The buzziest.
闪电再现  相信者增加
又有人拍到闪电侠的照片了
Another picture of the Flash came in.
看到没
See?
那一团红色吗
That red blur?
说不定是PS上去的呢
How do you know that wasn't photoshopped?
不是
It wasn't.
这不是恶作剧  也不是集体幻觉
It's not a hoax or a mass hallucination.
知道吗  每天都有不同的人
You know, every day, someone new
开始接受难以置信之事
accepts the impossible
开始相信他的存在
and believes in him.
你为什么就是不信呢
Why can't you?
我只相信我能看见的
I believe in what I can see.
只相信我能触摸到的
What I can touch.
我能感受到的
What I can feel.
所以我相信你
Which means I believe in you.
麻烦你了  谢谢
Do you mind? Thanks, man.
-早上好  -今早可真忙
- Hey. - Busy morning.
目击者声称他们看到了红衣侠
Witnesses reported seeing a red streak?
乔  你真该看看当时的场面
Joe, you should have seen it.
在场的每个人都想要杀了彼此
It was like everybody in here was trying to kill each other.
还好我及时赶到
I got here just in time.
那肯定是分散注意力的幌子
Well, it must've been a diversion,
因为保险库里少了五十万美金
because there's 1/2 million bucks missing from the vault.
钞票堆里有追踪器
There's a tracer in the cash stacks.
我们正试着找到信号
We're trying to find the signal.
还有  你知道是什么导致如此大的...
Meantime, any idea what could've caused such mass...
混乱
this?
有可能是神经毒素
A neurotoxin, maybe.
我要擦拭一下证物表面
I'm going to swab some surfaces,
看能不能找到什么
see what I can find,
但我觉得他们也许是...中邪了
but I think maybe they got... whammied.
你刚刚是说了"中邪"吗
Did you just say whammied?
我觉得非常愤怒
I got so angry.
我不敢相信自己做了这种事
I can't believe I did that.
我不会伤害任何人
I would never hurt anybody.
-你得相信我  -我相信你
- You have to believe me. - I do.
这座城市里正在发生一些事情
Something is happening in this city
而每个人都想装作什么事都没发生
and everyone wants to pretend like it isn't,
但实际是发生了的
but it is,
我们得拿出行动来
and I think we should do something about it.
我男友决定要在家进行健康饮食
My boyfriend has decided we need to eat healthy at home,
所以我只有上班时才能吃自己喜欢吃的
so work is now the only place I can eat what I like.
不好意思  警探  你刚刚说什么了
Oh, I'm sorry, were you saying something, detective?
那个红色物体  闪电侠
The blur, the Flash,
穿红色衣服的人
the man in the red suit--
无论你管他叫什么...
whatever he's called--
今早有人在银行看到他了
he was spotted at the bank this morning.
你是说那家被抢了五十万美金
You mean the bank that was robbed of 1/2 million dollars,
里面还有一堆人想要杀了彼此的银行吗
where a dozen people tried to murder each other,
而你觉得我们的注意力要放在
and you think our attention should be focused on
抓住圣诞老人上
catching Santa Claus.
我无法解释他怎么能这么快就往返于犯罪现场
I can't explain how he gets to and from crime scenes so fast.
我们得搞清楚这人是谁
We need to figure out who this guy is
他的目的是什么
and what he wants.
你该去问问你女朋友
You should ask your girlfriend.
她不是在写有关他的同人小说吗
She writes fan fiction about him.
乔  帮我说说话
Joe, help me out here.
不好意思  搭档
Sorry, partner.
从我八岁起  我就不相信圣诞老人了
I stopped believing in Santa when I was about eight.
早上好  发生什么了
Hey. What's going on in there?
我想艾迪是在尝试说服队长
I think Eddie's trying to convince the Captain
闪电侠已经变成公害了
that the Flash is a public menace.
你没搞错吧
Excuse me?
我花了这么多时间说服你
So after weeks of my trying to convince you
闪电侠真实存在
that the Flash is real,
既然你终于相信我了
Now that you finally do believe me,
你却想要抓住他
you're trying to have him arrested?
-你搞什么  -我谢谢你啊  巴里
- What the hell? - Thanks, Barry.
抱歉
Sorry.
不用担心  队长拒绝我了
No worries. The Captain shot me down.
我现在不想吃午餐
Look, I'm not feeling like lunch.
晚点见吧
See you later.
他只是嫉妒了
He's just jealous.
嫉妒闪电侠吗
Of the Flash?
他应该嫉妒吗
Should he be?
不该
No.
等会见
I'll see you later.
巴里  你得去尖端科研实验室了
Barry, you need to get to S.T.A.R. labs.
我会的  等我吃完饭
Yeah, I will. After I eat.
愤怒  仇恨  攻击
Anger, hate, aggression.
一名绝地武士渴望的不是这些东西
a Jedi craves not these things.
出自《星球大战5:  帝国反击战》
没人发现那是句台词吗
No one is feeling that quote?
在银行的每个人都兽化了
Everyone in the bank went total savage for,
大概五分钟
like, five minutes.
接着他们就恢复正常了
And then they were fine again.
愤怒是一种强大的情绪
Anger can be a powerful emotion.
如果这个超能力者能够调动
If this Metahuman can engender
受害者身上所有的愤怒情绪
irrational feelings of anger in his victims,
他可以造成很大的危害
he can do a lot of damage.
韦斯特警探帮忙拿到了
Detective West helped get a copy of the CAT scans
医院给银行所有人做的断层扫描
the hospital did on everyone at the bank.
快看
Take a look.
看这个
Well, look at this,
大脑中的情感中心
the emotion centers of the brains
依然有受到控制的迹象
are still showing signs of being overwhelmed.
尤其是控制执行能力的那部分区域
Particularly the area that controls executive function.
大脑的那部分是阻止人们去做那些
That's the part of the brain that stops people from doing
脑海中突然产生的无目的
whatever random and potentially destructive thing
以及可能产生破坏性的行为
that pops into their head.
你认为超能力者是怎么影响他们的
How do you think the meta does it to them?
这问题可提到点子上了
That's the 1/2 million dollar question.
今晚吉特见吗
如果你们弄明白了  打电话给我
Hey, if you guys figure it out, just give me a call, okay?
闪电侠又去屋顶跟爱瑞丝幽会吗
Is the Flash off to another rooftop rendezvous with Iris?
不是
No.
是的  不过她可能只是想问我
Yeah, but she probably just wants to ask me--
问闪电侠要写进博客里关于超能力者的事
I mean, you know, him--about meta-human stuff for her blog.
你想要点建议吗
Do you want some advice?
不管我要不要  你都会提建议的对吗
No matter what I say, I'm getting the advice, right?
不要牵涉其中
Don't get involved.
不管是作为闪电侠还是你
As the Flash or yourself.
你不希望成为令他们分手的第三者吧
You don't want to be the one to blame for their breakup.
好吧  我明白了
Okay. I hear you.
-爱瑞丝  -闪电侠
- Iris. - Flash.
要是能叫你的真名就好了
Be great to call you by your real name.
像拉尔夫之类的吗
You mean like Ralph?
你真名叫拉尔夫吗
Is your name Ralph?
你为什么想见我
What did you want to see me about?
我男朋友  他
My boyfriend, he's--
你们分手了吗
Did you guys break up?
没有
No.
他是警察  他认为你很危险
He's a cop and he thinks that you're dangerous.
他正试图说服他的上司  说你是个威胁
And he's trying to convince his boss that you're a menace
必须被阻止
that needs to be stopped.
我认为应该提醒你
I thought I should warn you.
无论如何  你该离开了
Anyways, you should probably go.
你不离开
You're not going.
巴里  你在吗
Barry, are you there?
-怎么了  -警察找到了
- What? - The police got a ping
现金里藏的追踪器发出的信号
from the tracer hidden in the stolen cash.
特警队正靠近帕斯街区1600号
SWAT team's closing in on the 1600 block of Pass.
别再干扰爱瑞丝的感情生活了  快去
Now stop ruining Iris' love life and go.
我得走了
I've gotta run.
我肯定你对每个姑娘都这么说过
I bet you say that to all the girls.
哪有其他的姑娘
What other girls?
他总是付现金
He always paid in cash.
-没见出什么问题  -他过来了
- Never seemed like trouble. - He's on the move.
-不许动  -站着别动
- Freeze! - Hold it right there!
-举起手来  -有什么问题吗  先生们
- Hands up. - Is there a problem, gentlemen?
切尔托
Certo.
转过来
Turn around!
切尔托  你在等什么  铐住他
Certo, what are you waiting for? Cuff him!
轮不到你来指手画脚
You don't tell me what to do.
趴下
Get down!
面具不错
Nice mask.
闪电侠   第一季第八集
真是件值得安慰的事
It's kinda comforting to know that no matter
不管去哪个城市  大贝利汉堡店
what city you go to, Big Belly Burger is always
味道依然不变
going to taste like Big Belly Burger.
你指的是多油多盐吗
You mean full of grease and salt?
我认为这才是他们的秘密配方
I thought those were the secret ingredients.
奥利弗回来了
Oliver's back.
我让了奥利弗半个小时的时间呢
By the way, I gave Oliver, like, 1/2 hour head start.
-你好  巴里  -你好  费利西蒂
- Hi, Barry. - Hey, Felicity.
你怎么样  狄格尔
How you doing, Dig?
你太快了
You're fast.
你们没告诉他我的事吗
Did you guys not tell him about me?
眼见为实  不然就是...
Seeing is believing, or...
胡说八道了
drooling.
谢谢你帮我解围  不过我能搞定
Hey, thanks for showing up back there, but I had that.
-我正打算进行下一步计划呢  -什么计划
- What, I was getting ready to make my move. - What move?
-直接去停尸房吗  -等等  你们几个
- The one to the morgue? - Wait, so what are you guys
-怎么会来中城  -我们来查案
- doing in Central City? - Working a case.
在星城发生了一起可疑的凶杀案  作案凶器
Suspicious homicide in the Starling where the murder weapon
是回旋镖
is a boomerang.
真帅
Cool.
说错了  真过分
I mean, awful.
我发现上面有氧化铁
I found traces of ironoxide on it.
我知道这个希望很渺茫  不过中城
I know it's a long shot, but Central City has
是全国氧化铁浓度最高的地方
the highest concentration of ironoxide in the country.
你知道吗  澳大利亚土著居民
Did you know Australian aboriginals
会用回旋镖狩猎  主要是猎袋鼠
use boomerangs to hunt? Mainly on kangaroo,
袋鼠是低脂肪高蛋白生物
which is a surprisingly low-fat source of prot--
我们正在查线索
We were following up a lead
后来听到了特警队的广播  就想着
when we heard the S.W.A.T. raid over the radio, and I thought
不如过来  围观一下你的"计划"
that I would come by... watch you make your move.
我有个表兄弟也被闪电击中
I had a cousin got hit by lightning once.
然后变成了结巴
He just developed a stutter.
我和我的队友
Well, my team and I
正在查一个超能力者  他会让人生气
are after a nasty meta-human who makes people angry.
真帅
Cool.
说错了  真过分
I mean, awful.
既然你们来了  不如我们组队吧
Well, since you guys are here, why don't we team up?
我帮你们找用回旋镖的凶手  你们帮我
I'll help you find your boomerang man, you can help me
-找这位怒火发射器  -荣幸之至
- find my super rage-a-holic. - We'd love to.
不  我们办完事就直接回去
No, we'll handle our business and head home.
想查到关于回旋镖的一切信息  最快的办法
The fastest way to find out everything we need to know
就是跟尖端科研实验室合作
about the boomerang is to sic S.T.A.R. labs on it.
知道我秘密身份的人已经够多了
Enough people know my secret identity.
好吧  那我去  他们已经知道我是谁了
Fine--I'll go. They already know who I am.
你可以送我过去  之后我们再会合
You can drop me off, and I will meet up with you later.
要不我送你吧
How 'bout I give you a lift?
你居然不惊讶吗
Man, that's not freaking you out?
走吧
Let's go.
你感觉怎么样
So what'd you think?
我觉得...
I think...
我的衣服着火了
My shirt's on fire!
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry!
幸亏我穿了内衣
I'm glad I decided not to go braless.
你们还记得费利西蒂吗
You guys remember Felicity?
这一幕绝对忘不了
I'll always remember this.
费利西蒂  见到你很开心
Hi, Felicity, it's so good to see you.
怎么回中城来了
What brings you back to Central City?
因为巴里吗
Not Barry?
不  不是巴里
No, not Barry.
我们不可能的
This? Not happening.
我们考虑了一下  然后觉得还是算了吧
We looked down that road and we said no, thank you.
他们懂了
They get it.
其实我来这里  是为了这个
Actually, I'm here because of this.
太棒了
Awesome!
这镖翼是什么材质的
What are the wings made of?
不确定  我觉得可能是什么合成材料
Not sure--I'm thinking some sort of composite
或是高密度塑料
or high-density plastic--
用碳纤维增强硬度  太奇怪了
Reinforced with carbon fiber. Oh, that's weird.
-感觉好像...  -它在振动
- It almost feels like it's-- - Vibrating.
-没错  -对
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我想去做几个测试
Oh, I wanna run some tests,
现在立刻马上
and I wanna run them right now!
关于我们要找的超能力者  有新线索了吗
Hey, you guys come up with anything new on our Meta?
今晚被影响的警员说  在失控以前
The officer who was affected tonight says he saw
他看到一道红光一闪而过
a flash of red before he lost control.
我觉得那位超能力者是通过视神经引起怒火的
I suspect the Meta is inducing rage via the ocular nerve.
威尔斯博士要见你
Oh, Dr. Wells wants to see you.
为什么我感觉像是
Why do I feel like I just got called
被叫来校长办公室了
into the principal's office?
星城治安维持者
Starling City vigilante.
目前他自称  绿箭侠
He calls himself the Arrow now.
是吗  闪电侠
Oh, does he...Flash?
等等  这是怎么了
Wait, what's the problem?
我们不信任他
We don't trust him.
你们根本就不了解他
You guys don't even know him.
我知道过去三年内
I know that he was wanted for murder
他就因涉嫌至少12起谋杀案而被通缉
in at least 12 different cases dating back three years.
我知道自从他开始在星城活跃以来
I know there's been at least two major terrorist attacks
至少发生了两起重大恐怖袭击事件
in Starling since he became active.
好吧  可是现在警方不追究他了
All right, but the cops there are cool with him now.
他不再杀人了
He doesn't kill people anymore.
那些被他射杀过的
And what about all the criminals
罪犯呢  他们就不算了吗
that he put arrows through? Those, what, don't count?
-他是英雄  乔  -你才是英雄  巴里
- He's a hero, Joe. - You're a hero, Barry.
你保护人们  给予人们希望与光明
You offer protection, hope, light.
那个人只会让他的城市陷入黑暗之中
What that man does is carry out a dark reckoning for his city.
这是一种残忍又暴力的实现正义的方式
It is a brutal, violent vision of justice,
这点我们有分歧
one we do not share.
你要是真的觉得他是英雄  随便你
You truly think he's a hero, fine, so be it.
但他不是你该学习的榜样
But he's not the kind you should be looking up to.
我的错  这怪我
That's my bad. That's on me.
我希望那个绿箭侠滚出我的城市
I want that Arrow out of my city.
今晚就走
Tonight.
告诉我  你真的觉得他做什么都很快吗
Tell me, do you think he can do everything really fast?
我是说  他吃了饭以后
I mean, like, how fast do you think he goes to the bathroom
多快就会去上厕所呢
after he's eaten something?
你就是这么帮我放哨的吗
This is you watching my back?
对付米拉库鲁士兵是一回事  但这...
Well, the Mirakuru soldiers are one thing, but this...
不管他现在能做什么
Whatever he can do now,
他都是我们去年见过的巴里
he's still the same Barry we met last year.
如果你那么强烈反对跟他合作
Well, if you're so adamant against teaming up with him,
我们为什么要来这里
what are we doing here?
他是个好孩子  我只是问个名字  狄格尔
He's a good kid, and it's just a name, Diggle.
是谁租下这个仓库的
The man who rents this storage unit--
他叫什么
I want...his...name.
你们要找的那个抢银行的坏人
The bad guy that you're after, the one who robbed the bank,
名字叫罗伊·G·巴布洛
his name is Roy G. Bivolo.
谢了  你怎么知道的
Uh, thanks. How did you find that out?
那人还活着吧
The guy's still alive, right?
我就问问
I'm just asking.
我还以为你不想帮忙呢
I thought you didn't want to help.
的确不想  那只是个名字
I'm not. It's just a name.
无脂加糖拿铁是费利西蒂的
One non-fat latte, extra sugar for Felicity,
黑咖啡是奥利弗的
and one coffee, black, for Oliver.
我给你煮了一壶新的
I brewed you a fresh pot, so...
谢谢
Thank you.
巴里  我能和你谈谈吗
Barry, um, can I talk to you for a second?
你在干什么
Ow. What are you doing?
你都没告诉我你认识奥利弗·奎恩
You did not tell me that you knew Oliver Queen.
-我认识奥利弗·奎恩  -天呐
- I know Oliver Queen. - Oh, my God,
他真人看上去更帅
He's even more handsome in person.
他的手臂有你的两倍粗
And his arms are, like, twice the size of yours.
严格上来说没有两倍
Technically they're not twice the size.
他就在我的三人名单上
He's on my three list.
什么三人名单
What's a three list?
就是这三个人可以让我不惜背叛艾迪
My list of three guys I'm allowed to cheat on Eddie with.
你一般不会碰到你名单上的人
You usually don't meet people on your list,
他现在就在我眼前  我根本转不开眼
But now here he is, and I just cannot stop staring at him.
费利西蒂  我发现你一直盯着我
Felicity, this is me noticing you staring.
我们得帮巴里处理他的案子
We need to help Barry with his case.
你为什么不想帮忙
Why don't you want to help?
因为巴里其实不需要我的帮忙
Because Barry doesn't really want my help.
只是他自己以为他需要罢了
He only thinks he does.
哈里森·威尔斯和收养巴里的警察爹
Harrison Wells and Barry's cop foster dad
都说你很危险  对他有不好的影响
both said you were dangerous and a bad influence.
巴里极力维护你
Barry defended you.
我要是不同意的话你就一直跟我讨价还价是吧
You're going to hock me about this until I say yes, aren't you?
我最擅长讨价还价了
I'm a hocker.
好吧
Okay.
-什么好吧  -我们会帮你抓坏蛋
- Okay, what? - Okay, we'll help you catch your bad guy.
太好了  超能力者
Great. Meta-human.
我不会叫他这个的  巴里
I am not calling him that, Barry.
做搭档吧
Partners?
好的
Partners.
你迟到了
You're late.
巴里  你能极速移动
Barry, how can you have super-speed
怎么还迟到呢
and still not be on time?
抱歉  我的超级拖延症可能中和了一些速度
Sorry, I guess the super-tardiness kinda neutralizes it.
我们在这怎么抓巴布洛
So how do we catch Bivolo here?
不  我们来这不是抓他  我们是来训练的
Oh, no, we don't here. We're here to train.
什么  像洛奇一样吗
What? Like Rocky?
我读了你朋友爱瑞丝关于闪电侠的博客
I read your friend Iris' blog post on the Flash,
我去了你战斗过的所有犯罪现场
and I visited all the crime scenes you fought at.
你不用睡觉的吗
Don't you sleep?
上月你拿下了一个叫莱昂纳多·史纳特的家伙
Last month You took on a man named Leonard Snart.
我们叫他寒冷队长
We call him Captain Cold.
我们晚点可以谈谈你给你的敌人
We can talk about you giving your enemies
取愚蠢代号的事
silly code names later.
你是说像跟死亡射手和女猎手一起喝咖啡吗
You mean like over coffee with Deathstroke and the Huntress?
重点是你和史纳特在列车上交手
The point is that you engaged Snart on a commuter train,
而他让列车脱轨了
which he derailed.
好吧  可能是有一些损失
Okay, there may have been some damage,
但我完成了任务  我是英雄
but I got the job done, I was the hero.
巴里  当你进入一个新的环境
Barry, when you approach a new environment,
你会检查每一个细节吗
do you case every inch of it?
你可以做到的  你有时间
You could. You have the time.
但你没有
But you don't.
你只是盲目地跑
You just run in blind.
巴里  拥有力量和拥有精确度
There's a difference, Barry, between having powers
是有差别的
and having precision.
当我找到你说
When I came to you thinking about
我要出去帮助人时
going out and helping people,
你说我很鼓舞人心
you said I could be an inspiration.
过这样的生活
Living this life...
不止需要面具
well, it takes more than a mask.
还需要纪律
It takes discipline.
既然你很可能跟我一样固执
And since you are probably as stubborn as I am--
这是要干嘛
What is that for?
你得跑到那边去
You're going to run over there,
再跑回来
you're going to come back at me,
然后会被箭射到
and you're going to get hit with an arrow.
不  我不会的
No, I'm not.
不  你会的
Yes, you are.
好吧
Okay, fine,
我就来幽你一默
I will humor you.
准备好了吗
Ready?
好了
Ready.
射得准
Nice try.
什么  你射中了我
What, you shot me?
听说你能很快愈合
I heard you heal fast.
天呐
Oh, God!
怎么了
Hey. What's up?
艾迪在又为他的案子请求成立特别小组
Eddie's making his case for the task force again.
但我以为队长已经拒绝他了
But I thought the Captain shot him down already.
显然他又找到了新的论点
Well, apparently he's got a new argument.
绿箭侠昨晚又出现了
The Arrow made another appearance last night.
你忘了告诉我你通过用箭射仓库看管员的腿
And you forgot to tell me that you got Bivolo's name
来拿到巴布洛的名字
from shooting that storage guy in the leg.
其实不是我射的他
Well, technically I didn't shoot him.
那你要怎么描述
Well, what word would you use to describe
你获知这个信息的方式
how you got this info?
我会用"严刑逼供"这个词
I'm gonna go with torture.
不是我  是绿箭侠弄到的
I don't--the Arrow gets results.
他是个疯子
He's a crazy man.
此刻我其实不反对你的看法
Look, I don't actually disagree with you at the moment,
但如果没有绿箭侠的话
but we wouldn't even have Bivolo's name
我们不会知道巴布洛的名字
if it weren't for the Arrow.
所以与其对他有看法  你应该谢谢他
So maybe instead of judging him, you should just be thanking him.
我这一生有两件事绝不会做
Two things I won't be doing in this life--
参加职业棒球赛和感谢那个疯子
playing professional baseball, and thanking that lunatic.
别动
Stay.
你听过色彩心理学吗
Have you heard of color psychology?
是那个说色谱可以改变情绪的理论吗
The theory that changes in the color spectrum can affect emotion.
能有个女人一起聊天真是太好了
It is so nice to have another woman to talk to.
我懂的
I know.
我想如果巴布洛运用颜色
I was thinking that if Bivolo uses color
来引发临时性精神错乱
to induce the temporary psychosis,
那没准我们可以用彩色灯光来反制
maybe we can use light and color to reverse it.
斯莫克小姐  能和您说句话吗
Miss Smoak, a word, if you please.
干什么  博士
Hey, what's up, doc?
抱歉  刚才那话真蠢
Sorry, that was dumb.
我可是麻省理工毕业的
Remember I went to M.I.T.
是  你很聪明
Yes, you're smart.
费利西蒂  我希望我的团队都是由熟人组建
Felicity, I like to surround my team with known quantities.
因为我发现未知事物
That is because I find the unknown
是毒素  很危险
to be toxic, dangerous.
绿箭就是未知事物
The Arrow is unknown.
我可以向你保证  威尔斯博士
I can assure you, Dr. Wells,
他一点都不危险
he's not dangerous.
对我们来说
To us.
对此我表示怀疑  而且
Well, of that, I have little doubt. And yet,
我发现自己有个难题
I find myself with a conundrum.
我如何相信一个
How can I completely trust a man
连名字都不知道的男人
when I don't even know his name?
所以  我希望你  斯莫克小姐
And so, I was hoping, Miss Smoak,
能够帮助我相信他
that you could help me trust him.
那兜帽底下的男人是谁
Who is he under the hood?
那不是我该吐露的秘密  威尔斯博士
That is not my secret to tell, Dr. Wells.
当然了
Of course.
我会自己查出来的
I'll figure it out on my own.
和奥利弗进行得怎么样
How'd it go with Oliver?
说实话  和我原先想象的那种合作
You know, to be honest, not exactly the partnership
不太一样
I thought it would be.
他真的用射箭那一套了吗
Oh, did he really do the thing with the arrows?
你知道他会射我吗
You knew he was going to shoot me?
基本上你看不出
Whoa, it is practically impossible to tell
奥利弗是不是在说笑
when Oliver's making a joke.
我们刚收到面部识别软件
Hey, we just got a ping from
也就是凌镜  传来的巴布洛信号
the facial recognition software on Bivolo, aka, Prism.
我们什么时候有面部识别软件了
Since when do we have facial recognition software?
-光明节快乐  -他在哪里
- Happy Chanukah. - Where can I find him?
路边摄像头刚拍到他进入了
Traffic cameras just caught him entering a residence
贾维斯168号的住所
at 168 Jarvis.
我们得让绿箭知道
We should let the arrow know.
我可以自己搞定  我之前干过
I can handle this solo. I've done it before.
巴里  我真觉得你得等着
Barry, I really think you need to wait--
费利西蒂  我不需要他的帮忙
Felicity, I don't need his help.
我就知道你会来找我
I knew you'd be coming for me.
我在银行看到过你的眼神
I could see it in your eyes at the bank.
当我让那些人互相伤害时
When I turned those people against each other,
你生气了
it made you angry.
来体验下真正的愤怒吧
Have some real anger.
没有黄斑损伤
No signs of macular damage.
你的视网膜和角膜似乎没受影响
Your retina and cornea seem unaffected.
我说了  我没事
I told you, I'm fine.
你说巴布洛让你中了邪
You said Bivolo whammied you.
你现在却不想揍人吗
No desire to go MMA on any of us?
不想
No.
我是说  他的眼睛有一瞬间
Yeah, I mean, something weird happened
变得很奇怪
with his eyes for a sec.
奇怪
Weird thing?
好像变成了红色
Yeah, everything went red.
你说的没错
You were right.
接下来巴布洛就跑了
Okay, next thing you know, Bivolo was gone.
显然他的能力对我没用  所以
Look, obviously his powers didn't work on me, so...
你单独面对他实在太愚蠢了
It was stupid for you to go out there alone.
你太冒险了
You take too many risks.
尽管你速度很快  冒险迟早会害了你
As fast as you are, that's going to catch up with you.
凯特琳  我不是罗尼
Caitlin, I'm not Ronnie.
你不要再像对待他一样对我
You gotta stop treating me like I am.
你说得没错  你并不是他
You're right. You're not.
怎么了
What?
你真是个惹人爱的小傻子
You are such a lovable dummy.
是奥利弗  他想再训练我一次
It's Oliver, he wants to have another session.
我保证他不会再射你了
I'm sure he's not going to shoot you again.
也许你应该穿个护甲
Maybe you should wear body armor.
你是在想新办法来羞辱我吗
Thinking of new ways to embarrass me?
我没在羞辱你  巴里
I'm not trying to embarrass you, Barry,
但是你昨晚独自去追巴布洛
but you went after Bivolo last night alone
而且把他跟丢了
and you lost him.
那你就从来没有失误过
And you've never had a misstep?
我当然也失误过
Course I've had missteps.
巴里  我过这样的生活已经快八年了
Barry, I have been living this life for almost eight years,
我遇见过你想象不到的各种事
encountering things that you can't even fathom,
而我还活得好好的
and I am still alive.
让我脱险的并不是速度
Not because super-speed kept me out of the ground.
而是我意识到  自己需要不断学习
It was because I realized that I needed to keep learning,
不断训练  不断变得更聪明
keep training, keep getting smarter,
在你学会这些之前  尽管你出发点是好的
and until you get that, despite your best intentions,
也只会带来更多伤害
you will do more harm than good.
我是看出来了
I finally see it.
你有点嫉妒我  对吧
You're a little bit jealous of me, aren't you?
像你这样的人  英俊多金
A guy like you, handsome, rich,
想找什么样的姑娘随便挑
can have any girl he wants,
嫉妒对你来说应该还是头一回
jealousy's probably a new emotion for you,
所以你可能对感受到的情绪
so you might be a little slow to get what it is
反应有点迟钝
that you're feeling.
-这就是你的想法  -没错
- That's your theory? - Absolutely.
你就继续训练  举重
So you can train, lift weights,
攀岩  直到心脏爆掉
climb that stupid barn till your heart explodes,
但你永远做不到像我这么快
but you'll never be as fast as I am.
你永远都成为不了我
You'll never be what I am.
而这会打击到你坚不可摧的自尊心  奥利
And that's gotta hurt your rock-hard pride, Ollie.
我跟费利西蒂说过你不需要我的帮助
I told Felicity you didn't want my help.
没错  你总算说对一些事了
Yeah. You're finally right about something.
艾伦  巴布洛的案子你查的怎么样了
Allen! Where are you with the Bivolo case?
我还在研究
I'm working it.
能说得更详细一点吗
Care to be more specific?
我问你问题时  你怎么不回答我
Hey, how about you answer me when I ask you a question?
你怎么不滚开
Hey! How about you back off?
你说什么
Excuse me?
我跟警局里的其他人一样努力工作
Look, I work just as hard as anyone in this building.
我不需要你一直指责我如何做好工作
I don't need you constantly berating me to do my job.
我完成之后就会给你的  好吗
When it's done, you will have it, all right?
不好意思  队长  他不小心吃错药
Sorry, Captain. He's having an allergic reaction
产生了过敏反应
to some bad medication.
记得提醒他  谁是他的上级
You remind him who answers to who.
你疯了吗
Have you lost your mind?
我厌倦了你这样对我说话
I'm so sick of seeing you talking to me like that.
他还是我们的上级
He's still our boss.
我知道追丢巴布洛这事让你不开心
Now I know you're upset about losing Bivolo--
等等  你就跟他一样
Wait, wait... you're just like him.
跟威尔斯  奥利弗  还有其他人一样
Like Wells, and Oliver, and everyone else my whole life
你们觉得我不能好好完成我的工作
that didn't think I could get the job done.
你想要帮我吗  乔  你要帮我吗
Do you want to help me, Joe? You want to help me?
那就把我爸爸从监狱里放出来
Get my dad out of prison.
把他关进监狱也有你的份  对吧
You helped put him there, didn't you?
巴里  你需要冷静下来
Barry, I need you to calm down.
不如我们一起去尖端科研实验室
Why don't we both take a ride to S.T.A.R. labs?
我很冷静
I'm calm! Okay?
当我不冷静的时候你会知道的
When I am not calm, you'll know.
我晚点打给你
Okay. I'll call you back later.
刚刚是绿箭侠
That was the Arrow.
他说巴里表现得不对劲
He says Barry is acting strangely.
怎么不对劲了
Strangely, how?
他像中邪了
He's been whammied.
他很生气  看上去很吓人
He was acting angry. It was scary.
他的眼睛好像在发光
And his eyes... they glowed.
大概是他的身体起了排斥作用
It's possible that his body is fighting off the effect,
所以对他的影响比较缓慢
So it's hitting him slower.
等他愤怒起来  可就真的不好了
When it comes to rage, that is not a good thing.
情绪被压抑得越久
The longer you suppress your emotions--
爆发就越大
The bigger the explosion.
可是他这么强  我们该怎么阻止他
Considering what he can do, how do we even stop him?
这时候冷冻枪就派上用场了吧
A cold-gun would come in real handy right about now.
-嘿  -就事论事嘛
- Hey. - I'm just sayin'.
我们没人能阻止巴里
None of us can stop Barry.
幸运的是  费利西蒂认识可以做到的人
Fortunately, Felicity knows someone who can.
我觉得你应该给奥利弗·奎恩打电话了
I think you better call back Oliver Queen.
我们需要绿箭的帮助
We're gonna need the Arrow's help.
你是想用这样的方式告诉我
Is this your way of telling me
圣诞礼物你想要卫星收音机吗
that you want satellite radio for Christmas?
我没生你的气
Look, I am not mad at you.
那最好  因为你没有理由生我的气
Good, 'cause there's no reason you should be.
艾迪  你和闪电侠都是想保护这座城市
Eddie, both you and the Flash care about protecting this city.
而且你们都愿意为此付出生命
You would both give your lives for it.
你们比你以为的要相像的多  好吗
You're more alike than you think, okay?
他不是坏人
He's not the bad guy.
你对他怎么知道这么多  爱瑞丝
How do you know so much about him, Iris?
我开始写博客后  他联系过我
He got in touch with me after I started the blog,
我也见过他几次
and I've seen him a couple times.
见过几次
A couple times?
你怎么不告诉我呢
Why didn't you tell me about this?
鉴于我认为他是个英雄
Well, given the fact that I think he's a hero,
你却觉得应该送他进监狱的事实
and you want to put him in jail,
你真的觉得有必要问出这个问题吗
do you really need to ask that question?
你怎么觉得我会不在意呢
How could you ever think I would be okay with this?
我听说你在找我
I heard you've been looking for me.
这么久以来  你一直都想抓我
All this time, you've been trying to catch me,
却被我先抓到了
and I caught you first.
看来你没好好读女朋友的博客吧
Guess you haven't read your girlfriend's blog.
艾迪  不要
Eddie, no!
我就知道绿箭是奥利弗·奎恩
Ooh, see I knew the Arrow was Oliver Queen.
我确实只把范围压缩到了150个人左右
I mean, I had it narrowed down to, like, a list of 150 people,
但他绝对是其中一个
but he was definitely on that list.
你有办法停止巴里的狂怒节吗
Do you have a way to stop Barry's rage-fest?
我有个想法
I have an idea about how to do that.
乔  我们需要你帮忙
Joe, we're gonna need your help.
我们得在他伤人前找到他
We need to find him first before he hurts somebody.
找到了
I have him.
面部识别在一个市区交通监控上找到了他
Facial recognition picked him up on a traffic camera downtown.
天呐
Oh, God.
艾迪
Eddie!
你以为你是谁啊
Who the hell are you, huh?
你以为你可以就这样插进来
You think you can just come along
想要什么就有什么吗
and get to have whatever you want?
谁给了你这样的权利
What gives you the right?
你在说什么啊
What the hell are you talking about?
你到底在做什么  你怎么了
What are you doing? What has happened to you?
我觉得很好
I feel fine.
你并不好
You are not fine.
你怎么知道  就因为你写关于我的文章
How would you know? Because you write about me?
你不了解我
You don't know me!
你不了解真实的我
You don't know who I am.
从来都不了解
You never did.
我知道你愿意冒着生命危险去帮助别人
I know that you have risked your life to help people,
拯救生命  会这样做的人
to save them! Someone who does that
不会突然转而伤害别人
does not suddenly turn around and want to hurt people.
求你
Please.
-快跑  -艾迪  快跑
- Run! - Eddie, run!
你需要镇定
You need to calm down.
你需要抓紧
And you need to hold on.
我希望他们能在巴里杀掉奥利弗
I just hope they can turn Barry back
之前把他变回来
before he kills Oliver.
我  我觉得更需要担心的是奥利弗
Me, I'd be more worried about what Oliver
会不会把巴里怎么样
might have to do to Barry.
巴里有超能力  奥利弗只有弓箭
Barry has superpowers. Oliver has a bow and arrow.
那你知道有多少人都死在了
Do you have any idea how many people
奥利弗那副弓箭之下吗
Oliver has killed with that bow and arrow?
反曲弓的箭头能以每秒三百英尺的速度前进
Recurve bow arrows can travel up to 300 feet per second,
差不多就是一小时两百英里
so, like, 200 miles an hour.
可巴里能跑得比那支箭快三倍
Barry can run three times that fast.
随便吧  奥利弗在这方面更有经验
Whatever. Oliver's been doing this a lot longer.
我认为经验最重要
My money's on experience.
我认为速度最重要
My money's on speed.
你们不是要现在这个时候
Please tell me you're not actually
讨论这些事情吧
having this conversation right now.
没射中
You missed.
不
No.
用在马身上的两千毫克镇定剂
2000 milligrams of horse tranquilizer
应该很快就能让你冷静下来
should be hitting you any time now.
你要去哪
Where you going?
我们还没分出胜负呢
We're not done!
你就只有这点能耐吗
Is that all you got?
奥利弗  起来
Oliver, get up.
你骗过我一次
Fool me once.
可我还是相信你  巴里
I still believe in you, Barry.
这样会有用吗
Is this even going to work?
只要让他看到正确的颜色
He just needs to see the right colors.
就是现在  乔
Now, Joe!
巴里  你还好吧
Barry, you okay?
这会是很特别的一次宿醉
Oh, this is going to be a special kind of hangover.
这么说
So...
他们打了个平手
it was a tie.
奥利弗
Oliver...
对不起
I'm so sorry.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
但我们还有个超能力者要处理
But we do still have your meta-human to take care of.
坦克里留下什么了吗
Anything left in the tank?
如果没有  就只有我们俩吧
Well, if not, there's two of us, right?
没错
Right.
你认为这样就能阻止我吗
You think this will stop me?
我会让你们把对方撕成碎片
I will make you tear each other to pieces!
你们全都带着怒火  叫喊着死去
You will all die screaming with rage!
废话连篇  没有一所监狱能关得住我
Blah, blah, blah, no prison can hold me.
这些话早就听过了
Heard it all before, pal.
再见  监狱
Adios, prison.
我喜欢彩虹大盗
I liked Rainbow Raider.
只有我才能给他们起名字
Okay, you don't get to pick the names.
这种监狱我也有一个
I have a prison like this.
在中国北方海域一个很荒凉的小岛上
Mine's on a nearly inhospitable island in the North China sea,
但是这个也行
but this works too.
只有少数的几个人知道我的身份
My identity is a closely-guarded secret known only to a few,
如果秘密被公开  就会危及到我的家人
and if it were to get out, will endanger my family,
以及我的朋友
my friends,
这样会助长
and it would embolden
我的敌人为报复我而伤害他们
my enemies to retaliate at me through them.
奥利弗想说的是
What Oliver is trying to say
他很高兴和你们一起共事
is that he had a lovely time working with you
并且了解你们每一个人
and getting to know each of you,
而且他等不及再次与你们共事
and he can't wait to do it again soon.
没错
Right.
他说的话听起来可不是这意思
You know, it didn't sound like that's what he was saying.
我可能不同意你的做事方式  可是
I may not agree with your methods, but...
-谢谢你  -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
如果我有一份
Hey. If I had a DNA sample
我无法完全分解的DNA样本
I was unable to fully break down,
你能帮我分离遗传标记吗
do you think you could isolate the genetic markers for me?
当然  样本从哪来的
Sure, what's the sample from?
金丝雀的尸体上来的
The Canary's murder.
当然了
Of course.
奎恩先生  我曾经见过你的父亲
Mr. Queen, I met your father once.
在慈善活动上
Charity event.
我们聊的其中一个话题就是你
One of the things we spoke of was you.
我想现在的你一定令他感到很自豪
I think he would be very proud of the man you've become.
谢谢
Thank you.
请叫我奥利弗
And please, call me Oliver.
博士有些不对劲
There is something off about that guy.
辛格队长批准了那个特别小组
Captain Singh approved the task force.
你要我相信闪电侠真的存在
You wanted me to believe the Flash was real.
现在我相信了
Now I do.
我相信他很危险
I believe he's dangerous,
我要把他抓起来
and I am going to take him in.
你怎么想
How do you feel about that?
我只知道...
All I know...
我对你的感觉
is how I feel about you.
你们要回去了吗
Hey! You guys heading home?
是的  我们可以拿点咖啡在路上喝
Yeah, we could use some javas for the road.
我给你们准备
I will hook you up.
-好  -谢谢
- Okay. - Thank you.
听着...
So listen...
我为我在训练场和昨晚在外面
I'm really sorry for what I said in the field
说的话感到非常抱歉
and then last night in the street.
我想把这一切都推到巴布洛
I wish I could say it was all because of whatever Bivolo
对我的影响上  但可能是我内心压抑着
did to me, but I guess I had
我自己都不知道的想法
more feelings bottled up than I thought.
你随时都可以找我倾谈
You can always talk to me.
好的  谢谢
Yeah. Thank you.
而且你说得对  我还有...
And you were right, I still have...
很多要学
a lot to learn.
还有一件事...
There's one more thing...
说出来你不会喜欢
and you're not going to like it.
是有关在我后背放箭吗
Does it involve you shooting me in the back?
不  是心
No. No, the heart.
你们不会有结果的
That's not going to work out for you.
为了你俩着想
You need to let her go,
你得放开她
for both of your sakes.
我们这样的人不能有女人
Guys like us don't get the girl.
准备好了吗
You ready?
-这是给你的  -谢谢
- This one's yours. - Thank you.
奥利弗
Oliver.
-你好吗  -很好
- How are you? - Good, good.
好久不见了
It's been a long time.
之后我们就没说过话了  我非常抱歉
We never spoke after, and I'm so sorry.
不  是我抱歉
No, I'm sorry.
我听说你母亲的事了...
I heard about your mother...
她非常爱你
She loved you very much.
是的
She did.
-我得离开了  -好
- I should get going. - All right.
那是谁
Who was that?
我以前认识的人
Someone that I used to know.
亲爱的
Hi, sweetheart.
我在给你买热巧克力
Yes, I'm just getting you a hot chocolate.
妈妈很快就回家了
Mommy will be home soon.
收到你的信息了
Got your message.
我想让你知道  昨晚...
I wanted you to know, last night...
那个人不是我
that wasn't me.
确实长得很像你
Sure looked like you.
没错  我被一个超能力者影响了
Yeah. I was affected by one of the Meta-humans.
他干扰了我的大脑
He messed with my head.
不过我现在没事了  我保证
But I'm okay now, I promise.
我为你辩护
I defended you.
大家都告诉我你只会给我带来危险
Everyone told me that you would bring me nothing but danger.
我父亲  巴里  艾迪...
My father, Barry, Eddie...
我不听他们的  我从来都不听他们的
I didn't listen to them. I never listened to them.
但现在我是时候听他们的了
But now it's time I did.
不要再联系我了  好吗
Don't contact me anymore, okay?
爱瑞丝...
Iris...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我也是
Me too.
瞧那人  比自动取款机好使多了
Look at that. Better than an ATM.
有人告诉你别在夜晚去高速公路闲逛吗
Anyone tell you not to hang out under the freeway at night?
你很有可能会被抢劫
You're liable to get robbed.
你身体在晃吗
You got the shakes, man?
你在发抖还是只是感觉冷
What are you, tweaking, or just cold?
我不冷
I'm not cold.